‪我准备好了！
[SpongeBob] I'm ready!
[grunts]
[SpongeBob sings theme]
‪NETFLIX 出品
‪原始的热带浅海
[narrator]The temperate, pristine,
shallow seas of the tropics.
‪无与伦比的美丽肥沃之地
A place of unparalleled beautyand fecundity.
‪这些岛屿滋养着‪海底充满朝气的生态系统
These islands play hostto a vibrant ecosystem below.
‪被称之为珊瑚礁的壮丽浩瀚海底生物
A vast organism knownas the coral reef.
‪这座水底都市
Life in this watery metropolis
‪在曲折中茁壮成长
thrives amongthe twists and turns,
‪在各个角落与隙缝中生存
nooks and cranniesand back alleys.
‪珊瑚礁边缘多姿多彩的地形中
And near the reef's edge,the varied and colorful terrain
‪有一座小镇
gives way to a small townby the name of…
‪名为比奇堡
Bikini Bottom.
[clam crowing]
‪在这里可以找到甲壳类动物
Here, one can findcrustaceans…
‪钱！钱！钱！
-[coins clinking]-Money! Money! Money!
‪海星
-…sea stars…-Mmm.
‪章鱼
Aww!
-…octopi…-[clarinet playing off key]
‪偶尔也会出现松鼠科学家
[cackling]
…the occasional squirrel/scientist…
‪早安 奥托‪你很快就能迎向全世界了！
Good morning, Otto.
You're almost ready for the world!
to become mastersover all organic life!
Huh?
‪对了 还有海绵
…and, oh, yes… the sea sponge.
‪这家伙和心爱的宠物窝牛‪快乐地生活着
This one lives happilywith his beloved pet snail…
‪蜗牛名为盖瑞
-…Gary.-[meows]
[SpongeBob snoring]
‪早安啊 盖瑞！
Oh, morning, Gary!
‪好恶心的蜗牛液体
Eww, snail trail. Yucky.
‪却令人感到异常舒缓
But oddly soothing.
‪早安 派大星！
Good morning, Patrick!
‪早安 海绵宝宝！
Good morning, SpongeBob!
‪早安 派大星！
Good morning, Patrick!
‪早安 海绵宝宝！
Good morning, SpongeBob!
‪早安 派大星！
Good morning, Patrick!
‪早安 海绵宝宝！
Good morning, SpongeBob!
‪早安 派大星！
Good morning, Patrick!
‪你们这两个傻子别吵了！
Would you two knuckleheadskeep it down out there?!
‪早安 章鱼哥！
[both] Good morning, Squidward!
[yells]
‪来吧 盖瑞！吃早餐！
[SpongeBob] Come on, Gary! Breakfast!
‪（盖瑞）
‪（海绵宝宝）
["It's Always Summerin Bikini Bottom" playing]
‪不用客气
-[belches]-You're welcome.
‪谁要抓痒痒？
[laughs] Who wants a belly scratch?
‪我好爱你 盖瑞
I love you so much, Gary.
[meows]
‪看看这是什么？
What's this?
‪我们等你把那个排出来吧
Okay, that'll come out later.
‪海绵宝宝：营救大冒险
‪我像是生活在超现实边缘
♪ Living like I'm on the edgeOf surreality ♪
♪ But I know everything is gonna be cool ♪
♪ As long as you're here with me ♪
[whistling melody]
‪我们会替彼此分忧
♪ We're gonna lighten upEach other's load ♪
‪一同面对前方的颠簸道路
♪ When bumps and curvesCome on the road ♪
‪只要我们齐心协力
♪ 'Cause we are all in it together ♪
‪誓死不渝
♪ And that's forever ♪
‪比奇堡四季如夏
♪ It's always summerIn Bikini Bottom ♪
‪（开麦之夜）
[laughing]
‪到了十二月份‪我们仍唱着开心的歌谣
♪ And in December ♪
♪ We're singing la-di-da-da ♪
‪比奇堡四季如夏
♪ It's always summer in Bikini ♪
♪ In Bikini Bottom ♪
‪没有什么比这个更好了
♪ It doesn't get better than that ♪
‪钱！钱！钱！
-[clock chimes, whirs]-Money! Money! Money!
[cackling]
‪糟糕！我要想早点的话 就快迟到了
Ooh! I'm lateif I'm gonna be early.
-[meows sadly]-Oh, don't worry, Gare-Bear.
‪别担心 盖瑞宝贝 在你还来不及说
I'll be back before you can say,
‪“他为何残忍地抛下我？”‪我就回来啦
"Why did he cruellyabandon me like that?"
[laughs]
[meows sadly]
[bell chimes]
‪新一天的开始也是令人头疼的一天
[sighs] Another day, another migraine.
‪在那小子出现之前至少能有片刻安宁
At least I'll get a little peaceand quiet before that little--
‪早安 章鱼哥！‪真是美好的早晨 对吧？
-Good morning, Squidward!-[shrieks]
And isn't it a lovely morning?
‪不 我不要跟你说话
Nope. Not talking to you.
‪我今天尤其没兴趣参与你的胡闹事
I'm especially not getting involved
‪每次吃亏的总是我
in any of your nonsense today.
I always end upwith the wrong end of the stick.
‪好吧 章鱼哥
Okay, Squidward.
‪你该知道‪老格特鲁德近来变得十分挑剔
[sighs]
But you should knowthat Old Gertrude's
getting prettyfinicky these days.
‪老格特鲁德？那是什么人？
Old Gertrude?Who the kelp is that?
‪你与她共事多年！她是厨房里的烤架
You've worked with herfor years!
She's the eight-burner grillin the kitchen.
‪真是没完没了
It never ends.
‪若要开火就得先激起她的火花
Anyway, to fire her up,
you've got to spark her flintsmanually and then…
‪再轻轻扭动她的开关
jiggle her gas jets just a little.
‪接着说她最喜欢的故事
And then read her favorite story:
‪“能干的小干锅”
"The Little Griddle Who Could."
‪第二章
Chapter Two:
‪肉饼说：“但我们刚离开冰箱‪仍冷冰冰的”
"But we are fresh fromthe freezer," said the patties,
and we're c-c-c-cold."
‪小干锅回答：“别担心‪我会让你们感到暖烘烘的”
"Don't worry,I'll get you nice and warm,"
said the Little Griddle.
‪我刚刚说了 我没兴趣
What'd I just say?I am not interested.
‪别把我牵连在内！
Don't involve me!
[groans]
‪你说什么 章鱼哥？章鱼哥？
What'd you say, Squidward?Squidward?
‪没关系的 章鱼哥‪反正我一直都会在
Okay, Squidward, doesn't matter.I'll always be here anyway.
‪真是不幸
Unfortunately.
‪别偷懒 章鱼先生！快干活！
Stop yer loafing, Mr. Squidward!
There's workto be done around here!
‪所有蟹堡王成员注意！
Attention, Krusty crew!
‪集体集合！
All hands on deck,front and center!
‪是的 蟹堡王船长！
Aye-aye, Cap'n Krabs, sir!
‪谁要跟我再来趟赚钱的冒险？
Now, who's ready to set sail
on another adventureof making me money?
‪-出发吧 船员！‪-是的 船长！
-Get moving, sailor!-Sir, yes, sir!
‪升起彩色旗子！
Raise the colors!
‪举起主帆！
Hoist the mainsail!
‪（蟹堡王）
‪部署烟囱！
Deploy smokestacks!
‪（客满）
‪（开始营业）
[all yelling]
‪哦 这般景象真是百看不腻
[chuckles] Oh, never gets old.
[Plankton cackles]
‪珍惜这有限的时光吧 蟹老板
Enjoy it while you can,Mr. Eugene Krabs.
‪（投入钱币）
-[cackles]-[beeping]
‪搞什么？
What the…?
‪该死的机器！
[growling] Stupid machine!
‪我刚才在做些什么？哦 是的
Where was I? Oh, yeah.
[cackling]
‪我今晚将实施‪第3087号的邪恶计划
Tonight I launchEvil Plan Number 3,087
‪夺走蟹堡王肉饼的秘方！
and finally take possession
of the Krabby Patty secret formula!
‪真是棒 又一个邪恶的计划
Great. Another evil plan.
‪又一个邪恶计划不好吗？
What's wrong with another evil plan?
‪没什么 只不过我们记录失败的墙‪快被填满了
Oh, nothing, it's just we're runningout of room on the Wall of Failure.
‪记录失败的墙？
Wall of Fai--?
[servos whirring]
‪凯伦 你为何要收集这些？
Karen, why do you keepcollecting these?
‪作为纪念
Heh. Memories.
‪今晚不同以往
Hmm! Well, tonight…is gonna be different.
‪我的电脑妻子凯伦‪每当我想偷走那个秘方时
Hee-hee! You see, Karen,my computer wife,
every time I've triedto steal that formula,
‪蟹老板都试图阻扰我
Krabs has tried to thwart me.
‪不是蟹老板
Mm-mm, not Mr. Krabs.
‪但今晚…你说什么？
But tonight, that all-- What?
‪阻扰你的不是蟹老板 亲爱的
It's not Mr. Krabs, sweetheart.I've checked the data.
‪我查过数据 问题人物是海绵宝宝
It's SpongeBob who's the problem.
‪你好
Hello.
‪哦 烦死了 跟那傻子有什么关联？
Oh, fish sticks.
What could that boobhave to do with it?
‪他其实一点也不傻
Boob savant, you mean.
‪一直以来搞乱你计划的是海绵宝宝
SpongeBob is the onewho keeps foiling your plans,
‪-而非蟹老板‪-惊喜！
not Mr. Krabs.
‪别胡说八道了 凯伦 肯定是蟹老板
Oh, nonsense.
It's Krabs, Karen, I know it is.
‪今晚 我终于能
And tonight,I will finally extract…
‪复仇！
my revenge!
[evil laughter]
‪你会迟回吗？
Will you be late?
‪像我这般天才‪是不被时间限制的 凯伦
You can't put a clockon genius, Karen.
‪上菜！快！
-[bell dings]-Order up! Move it, let's go!
‪是的 大厨！
Aye-aye, Chef!
‪请好好享用你点的蟹堡王肉饼！
One for you.Enjoy your Krabby Patty. Enjoy!
‪上菜！快啊 海绵宝宝！
[rings bell] Order up!
Come on, SpongeBob!
‪-炸物大厨海绵宝宝驾到！‪-炸物大厨海绵宝宝驾到！
-Coming, Fry Cook SpongeBob!-Coming, Fry Cook SpongeBob!
[all laughing]
[sighs]
‪-你好啊 海绵宝宝！‪-嗨 珊迪！
-[bell rings]-Hiya, SpongeBob!
[all] Hi, Sandy!
‪你知道吗？将来一切都会变自动化
Did you know that in the futureeverything will be automated?
‪真的？肚子疼也会自动化吗？
-Really? Even stomachaches?-[laughs]
‪我要问蟹老板是否愿意‪成为我新科技的早期采用者
I'm gonna seeif Mr. Krabs wants to be
an early adopterof my new technology.
‪什么？你要用机器人来取代我？‪别这么做！
Wait, what?
You're gonna replace mewith a robot? Don't do it!
‪才不是 傻瓜 那种事迟早会发生的
No, silly, that's gonna happen anyway.
‪我说的是更具创新性的初创企业
This is something much moreinnovative and start-uppy.
‪我只给你六十秒
You have sixty seconds.
‪它的名字叫做奥托！
Its name is Otto!
‪我的名字叫奥托 能如何为您服务？
-[whirring]-My name is Otto.
How may I serve you?
‪这是一个全自动化的餐馆老板
It's an automatedrestaurant owner.
‪全自动化？
Hmm. Automated?
‪听起来价格昂贵 没兴趣
Sounds expensive. Not interested.
‪奥托无需领取薪酬
Otto doesn't require a salary.
‪它也能做出冷酷无情的抉择
And it can make cold,heartless decisions
‪像是解雇人 因为它没心没肺
like firing people,because it doesn't have a heart.
‪可不是
-Ow.-You don't say.
‪-你被解雇了！‪-太棒了！
-You're fired.-Amazing!
‪我爱钱 我好爱钱
I love money. I love money.
‪一台冰冷毫无感情的机械机器人
A cold, unfeeling mechanical robot
‪就像我自己冷冰冰无情的甲壳心
after me own cold,unfeeling crustacean heart.
‪我会接受并好好培育奥托‪待他如亲生儿子
I'll take it and nurture it
and I will love Ottolike he was me own son.
Yippee! You're not gonnaregret this, Mr. Krabs.
‪-你被解雇了‪-那真是百听不厌
You're fired.
Oh, I could listen to that all day.
‪我是说真的 你不是我们的合适人选
[Otto] No, seriously.
We decided to go ina different direction.
‪你被解雇了
You're fired.
‪什么？
[nervous chuckle] What?
‪别逼我叫来保安
Don't make me call security.
‪-你被解雇了‪-你才被解雇了！
-You're fired.-No, yer fired!
‪-不 你被解雇了‪-你被解雇了 你这讨人厌的机器！
-No, you're fired.-Yer fired, ye infernal machine!
‪我没被解雇 你被解雇了
-I'm not fired, you're fired.-[shrieks]
‪（机械回收费：5美元）
‪虐待机器人
Robot abuse. Robot abuse.
-Huh?-Huh?
[chuckles]
‪你被解雇了
[slurring] You're fired.
‪这是什么玩意？
[Plankton] What the heckis this thing?
‪不知道 但我要带回家 可爱极了
[Karen] I don't know,but I'm taking it home.
‪什么？
-It's so cute.-What?!
‪来吧 小机器人 我们去吃宵夜
Come on, little robot.Let's get you some supper.
‪-这一点也不好笑 凯伦‪-安静点 痞老板
-Not even funny, Karen.-Quiet, Plankton.
‪-别听他说‪-凯伦！
-Shh, Don't listen to him.-Karen!
‪我爱你 妈妈
[Otto] I love you, Mom.
[sighs]
‪（已打烊）
‪你离开前得确保这厨房‪被打扫干净 小子
‪海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob! Be sure thiskitchen's in shipshape shape
before ye head out, boy.
‪是 蟹老板先生
[French accent]Oui, oui, Monsieur Boss Man Krabs.
‪有我办事 这厨房肯定一尘不染
Once I am done here, zees kitchen
shall be completely spotless.
‪随你怎么说吧 对了！
-[giggling]-Whatever.
‪我在六号桌找到这个‪未食用过的蟹堡王肉饼
Oh! I found this uneatenKrabby Patty on table six.
‪-你知道该怎么做‪-蟹老板！我会妥当处理掉
You know what to do with it.
Right away, Mr. K!
I'll see that it's disposed of properly.
‪谁说要处理掉？
[shrieks] Who said anythingabout disposing of?
‪我们明天再拿来卖
We'll sell it again tomorrow…
‪在我们的复古风遗赠手工餐点上推出
on our legacy artisanal vintagethrowback menu.
[both laugh]
‪晚安！
Good night!
‪我还是赶紧打扫吧
Oh! I better start cleaning.
[humming]
‪我准备好了！
I'm ready!
‪（小心地面湿滑！）
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
‪晚安了 格特鲁德！‪晚安 炸锅 晚安 肉饼
Well, good night, Gertrude!
Good night, fryer.Good night, patty.
‪晚安 腌黄瓜
Good night, pickles. Mwah!
[door shuts]
[lid bangs, rattles]
‪晚安 海绵宝宝
Good night, SpongeBob.
‪你好啊 蟹堡王肉饼！
Hello, Krabby Patty!
‪此刻
And now…
‪是动手的时机
Just got to get it.
‪太好了！
[cackling] Yes!
‪（投入钱币）‪等等 不要
Wait, wait. No.
‪不要 不！
No. No!
‪愚蠢的投币式…
Stupid coin-operated…
‪过来啊
Come here, come here…
Oh!
‪大成功！
Bingo!
‪快到爸爸这里来
Come to Papa.
‪只需几分钟
In just a few minutesthe formula will be mine!
‪（分析完毕）
[printer whirring]
‪太好了！蟹老板的快餐帝国将失败
Yes! Krabs's fast-food empire will fail
‪比奇堡将由我统治
and I will rule Bikini Bottom,
‪成为新一任的废食国王！
as its new slop king!
[guffawing]
‪我就知道会这样！
-I knew it!-[yelling]
‪秘方！
[Plankton groans]
‪我就知道钥匙留在这里‪我真是个傻瓜
-The formula!-I knew I left my keys in here.
Oh, silly me.
‪快给我过来！
Come here, you! [grunting]
‪没钥匙 真是奇怪 到哪去了？
Huh. No keys. That's weird.Where could they be?
‪好极了！不行
Yes! No.
Ooh! Ow!
‪钥匙 你在哪？
[SpongeBob] Keys, where are you?
‪快显示钥匙的位置吧！
-Come on, show me keys!-[screams]
‪到手了！
[gasps] Gotcha!
Ha-ha!
[whirring]
‪不 不要！
No. No!
[screams]
They were in my pocketthe whole time!
[laughs]
‪问题人物是海绵宝宝
[Karen] It's SpongeBob who's the problem.
‪我现在明白了
I get it.
‪（与此同时）
‪就在此时 在七海的统治者
[narrator] Meanwhile, at the palaceof King Poseidon…
‪波塞冬国王的宫殿里
…ruler of the Seven Seas.
‪（波塞冬宫殿 赌场）
‪大臣！
[Poseidon] Chancellor!
-Chancellor!-[Chancellor humming]
‪大臣！
Chancellor!
‪怎么了 殿下？您召唤我？
Yo. What's up, sire?You sent for me?
‪大臣 看看我！
Chancellor, look. Look at me!
‪三千岁的皮肤状态
3,000 years oldand check out my skin.
Ageless, sire. Looking fresh.
‪这都归功于我的臣子们 对吧？
Ha! I owe it to my subjectsto look fabulous,
‪您还有其他义务在身 殿下‪像是统治国家之类的要事
don't you think?
There are other obligations, sire.
‪我需要您在这些税项和法令
Like ruling and stuff.Let's see…
I need your signatureon these taxes, decrees,
‪以及此宣战书和我的薪水单上签名
this here declaration of warand my paycheck.
‪-是吗？‪-是的
-Is that right?-Yeah.
‪好吧
-[both chuckle]-Very good.
[both laughing]
‪天啊 大臣 你何时才能学会‪专注于真正重要的事？
Oh, Chancellor,
when will you learn to focuson what really matters?
‪君主政权与他自身的‪皮肤护理制度同样强大
A monarch's regimeis only as powerful
as his skin care regime.
‪我同意
Word. Mm-hm.
‪有些人甚至说我长得像希腊神
You know, some say I have a facelike a Greek god.
‪您确实是位希腊神
Well, you are a Greek god, so…
‪-等等 那是一条皱纹吗？‪-在哪？
Whoa! Wait, is…
-Is that a wrinkle?-Where?
‪是的！是皱纹！
It is! It's a wrinkle!
‪我看上去像被遗忘在冰箱里‪干巴巴的老鳄梨！
I look like an old avocado
that's been leftand forgotten in the fridge!
‪又来了
Here it comes.
‪我好丑！
I'm ugly!
‪那个有眼睛的圆壳爬行物‪到底在哪？
‪放到哪去了？
Oh, now, where is it?
The crawly thing withthe round shell and the eyes.
-Where is it?-[playing fanfare]
‪在这里 殿下 您的皇家蜗牛
Here you go, sire. Your Royal Snail.
‪哦 谢谢你
Oh! Oh, oh, thank you.
‪这类软体动物的复兴能力‪犹如做过一千次的面部护理
This mollusk hasthe rejuvenating power
-of a thousand facials.-[meows]
‪什么？怎么是空的？
What?! Is it empty?
[coughing]
‪快拿走！立即给我送上‪另一只海蜗牛！
Take it away!
Bring me another sea snailat once!
‪大臣！
-[indistinct whispering]-Uh-oh.
‪我实话实说吧 已没有蜗牛了
-Chancellor!-Okay, uh…
Full disclosure, man, uh…We're out of snails.
In fact, the entiresnail population has been, uh…
‪该怎么说呢？已被耗尽了
What's the word?Oh, yeah… depleted.
‪-你的意思是没有蜗牛了？‪-确实没有蜗牛了
You're telling me there are…
-no more snails?-There are no more snails.
‪-你确定？‪-我十分有把握
-And you're confident of that?-Relatively confident.
[shrieking]
‪大臣 为了赫耳墨斯‪我愿意用我的王国换取一只蜗牛！
Oh, Chancellor,for the love of Hermes,
my kingdom for a snail!
‪不行 这么做太仓促了
No, no, no. I'm being hasty.
‪我愿意用半个王国换取一只蜗牛！
Half my kingdom for a snail!
‪不 这应当做为恩赐‪我将恩赐任何送我蜗牛的人
No, no, no, a boon. Yes.
I'll grant a boon to whomevershall bring me a snail.
‪明白 我会起草法令 殿下
Gotcha.I'll draw up the decree, sire.
‪（皇家法令）
-[whip cracks]-[whinnying]
‪来自波塞冬国王的皇家法令？
A Royal Decreefrom King Poseidon?
‪“至所有海洋公民‪国王立即寻求一只蜗牛
"To all citizens of the sea,
the King requires a snail at once…
‪什么皮肤保养之类的事”
blah blah blahskin care blah blah--"
‪等等
Wait a minute.
‪蜗牛？
A snail?
‪这太完美了
No, it's too perfect.
‪能够同时去除盖瑞和海绵宝宝
Get rid of Gary,get rid of SpongeBob.
‪太好了
Oh, yeah.
[cackling]
‪盖瑞 我到家了！
Gary, I'm home!
‪盖瑞宝贝？你在哪 朋友？
Gare-Bear?Hey, where are you, buddy?
‪盖瑞？
Gary?
‪你肯定在…不在
You must be in the-- No.
‪盖瑞？
Gary?
‪盖瑞？‪盖瑞？
‪盖瑞？盖瑞！
Gary? Gary, Gary, Gary! Gary!
‪盖瑞！盖瑞去哪了？
Gary! Where's Gary?
‪盖瑞！
Gary!
[panting]
‪（蜗牛走失 请联系海绵宝宝）
‪盖瑞 你在哪？
Gary, where are you?
[panting]
‪哦 盖瑞
[sniffles] Oh, Gary.
[sobbing]
‪自遇见你那天起 我就爱着你
I loved you sincethe first day we met.
‪（珊瑚夏令营）
[children yelling]
[snail meows]
‪你好啊 小蜗牛
Hello, little snail.
[giggles]
[meows]
[laughs]
‪你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
‪是“盖瑞”吧？
[meows]
"Gary", huh?
‪你好 盖瑞
-[meows]-Well, hi, Gary.
‪你想交个朋友吗 盖瑞？
Gary, do you want to be friends?
[meows]
‪我也是
Me, too.
[sobbing loudly]
‪海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob! SpongeBob!
‪海绵宝宝！我找到这张传单‪盖瑞走失了！
Hey, SpongeBob!I found this flyer.
Gary's missing!
[SpongeBob sniffling]
‪我知道 派大星
I know, Patrick.
‪海绵宝宝？
SpongeBob?
‪派大星 盖瑞若出什么事的话
Oh, Patrick, if something wereto happen to Gary, I, well…
‪我真不知道该怎么办
I don't know what I'd do.
Hey! Maybe he left a clue.
-[toy squeaks]-Oh!
‪看！这是个线索！
[gasps] Look! A clue!
‪盖瑞被绑架了！
[gasps] Gary's been snailnapped!
‪并被带去失落的大西洋城！
And taken to The Lost Cityof Atlantic City!
‪真的吗？
[chewing] Oh, really?
‪那太棒了！
That's awesome!
‪我们现在知道他在哪
[spits] Now we know where he is.
Mm.
‪这一点也不棒 派大星 这里写着
Not really that awesome, Patrick.
‪“波塞冬称之为家的闻名浮华宫殿
Listen to this.
"Made famous by the glitzy palacePoseidon calls home.
‪失落的大西洋城是个可怕
The Lost City of Atlantic Cityis a scary,
‪也道德沦陷的堕落之地”
vice-ridden cesspoolof moral depravity."
‪哇 不会吧 那地方也被丢失了？
Wow. All that, and it's lost, too?
‪“波塞冬国王已证实‪自己是一个异想天开的暴君
"King Poseidon has provenhimself a whimsical tyrant,
‪以斩首方式将臣子处死而闻名
known for executing his subjectsby beheading them
‪并通过奢侈华丽的表演形态来展示
in a flamboyant floor showextravaganza.
‪我们对想来此地旅游的人‪提供的建议是
Our advice for thosetravelling here is…
‪不要来”
…don't."
‪这个波塞冬国王‪听起来像个很难搞的人
[gulps] This King Poseidonsounds like a tough customer.
Aw, so what?This is about friends.
‪朋友是不会让彼此‪成为他人脸上的护肤品！
And friends don't let friendsbecome somebody else's face cream!
‪朋友不会那么做
Not what friends do.
‪要是这趟旅途危险可怕呢？
-So what if it's dangerous and scary?-So what!
‪那又怎样！
‪会有什么能阻止我前往那里救出盖瑞
What is stopping me right nowfrom going there, rescuing Gary
‪并对抗这个波塞冬国王呢？
and standing up to thisKing Poseidon, huh?
‪-我不知道！‪-我知道！
-I don't know!-Well, I do!
‪-是什么？‪-我…
-What is it?-I…
‪缺乏勇气
…don't have the courage.
[sniffling]
[wailing]
Tartar sauce!
What's the next best thingto courage?
‪-解析能力？‪-不
-Resolve?-No.
‪-坚忍不拔的毅力？‪-不是
-Fortitude?-Nah.
‪-承诺？‪-也不对
-Commitment?-Nope.
‪-必要的资金？英勇？‪-全都不对
-Wherewithal? Bravery?-Mm-mm. No.
‪-勇猛不屈？坚毅？‪-什么？才不是
-Valor. Grit?-What? No.
‪英雄主义？豪勇？有气魄？
-Heroism? Gallantry?-Uh-uh. Nah.
‪是哥们！一个帮手！
-Moxie.-A buddy! A wingman!
‪一个帮手？
A wingman?
‪一个朋友
A friend.
‪真的吗 派大星？你要跟我一同去？
Really, Patrick?You'd go with me?
‪没错 我会跟在你身后！
Yeah… right behind you!
‪我嗅到的是公路之旅的味道吗？
Do I smell a road trip?
‪那可能是我的口气
[gasps] That could be my breath.
[both laughing]
‪好的
Okey-dokey.
‪我们来拟定计划‪派大星 你负责安排运输
Now, let's drill down on a plan.
‪切记 我不会开车 你也没有车子
Pat, you're in charge of transpo.
Just remember, I don't driveand you don't have a car.
Oh…
[motor rumbling]
‪看路！
Beep, beep!
‪嘿 各位！
Hey, boys!
‪不知道你们是否用得着这老旧东西
Don't know if you have any usefor this old thing,
‪像是用来进行任何旅行或救援任务
if you're going on any trips or journeys
or quests or rescue missions.
‪若有需要的话 奥托能送你们上路
But if you are, Otto is your ticket.
‪奥托！
[both] Otto!
‪你们只需告诉奥托要去哪就行了！
Just tell ol' Otto where you want to goand it will take you there!
‪请上车
All aboard.
‪-你被解雇了！‪-酷毙了！
-You're fired.-Cool!
‪一艘自动驾驶的船
A self-driving boat.
‪谢谢你 痞老板 你最棒了！
Thanks, Plankton. You're the best!
‪可不是 再见了
I know, I know. Bye-bye.
‪-奥托 去找盖瑞‪-明白了
-Otto. Find, Gary.-You got it.
[tires screeching]
‪不 派大星 你得说得更详细
No, Patrick.You got to be more specific.
‪奥托 去找蜗牛盖瑞
Otto, find Gary the snail.
‪重新计算中
[Otto] Recalculating.
[Patrick and SpongeBob yelling]
‪让我试试看吧
Ugh. Here, let me try.
‪把他们带去失落的大西洋城
Take them toThe Lost City of Atlantic City
‪永不归来！
and don't ever come back!
‪用稍微夸张的语气往往能事半功倍
Never hurts to employ a little hyperbole.
‪能服务您是我的荣幸
It is my pleasure to serve you.
[both yelling]
‪一路顺风 各位
[cackles] Bon voyage, boys.
‪我准备好了 他们死定了
I'm ready. I'm ready. They're dead.
‪这就像哥们电影里的情节
This is gonna be likeone of those buddy movies.
‪我们是好哥们！
We're the buddies!
‪-我不确定这是否相同 派大星‪-为何不呢？
[chuckles] Not sure that really applies,Patrick, but--
‪我们是为共同目标出发的两个家伙
Why not?
We're two dudes setting outwith a common goal.
‪我们在途中会为一点蠢事争吵而闹翻
We'll argue about something dumb,fight and break up…
‪最终却意识到‪我们不能没有彼此而复合
Only to come back together when we realize
neither could do it without the other.
‪这简单而神奇
It's simple yet magical.
‪是的
[SpongeBob] Yeah.
‪我感觉这更像单一英雄的旅程
It feels more to me likethe journey of a singular hero,
‪他排除万难 战胜逆境
who against all odds,triumphs over adversity.
‪我说是哥们电影‪你非得说成愚蠢的事
[snorts] I say buddy movie
and you say, oh, whatever thatdumb thing was you just said.
‪愚蠢的事？你是说我很愚蠢？
Oh, really? Dumb thing?
‪派大星 你这人真是讽刺
I'm dumb?Oh, I love your sense of irony, Patrick.
‪谢谢你 我也喜欢这种‪“风驰”的感觉
Thank you.I love my sense of ironing, too.
‪要不是你脑子进水 这还真是讽刺！
Maybe if your headwasn't packed full of sand,
you could have ironing!
‪脑子进水也好过跟你一样‪脑袋死板板！
Well, better a head full of sand
than a head full of rocks, like yours!
‪-够了！停车！‪-是的 快停车 奥托！
Ah! That's it! Stop the car!
Yeah, stop the car, Otto!
[brakes squeal]
[both yelling]
‪（海牛兄弟律师行）
‪我很抱歉 派大星
[rueful chuckle] Sorry, Patrick. Really.
‪我不该说你脑袋死板板
I shouldn't have saidyou have rocks in your head.
‪我也不该说你脑子进水
I shouldn't have saidyour brain was made of sand.
‪那样说实在恶毒也愚蠢
That was mean and dumb.
‪我们一笔勾销吧？
Okay. Let's just forget it, huh?
‪这事从没发生过！
Never happened!
[grunts] Uh-huh.
["On The Road Again" playing]
‪上车吧 各位
OTTO: Hop on in, guys.
‪我们又重新上路了
♪ On the road again ♪
‪不要
Ha, ha, ha!
‪跟朋友一同创作音乐‪才是我最爱的人生
Nope.
♪ The life I love is makingMusic with my friends ♪
‪我迫不及待再次展开旅程
♪ And I can't wait to getOn the road again ♪
[Otto laughing]
[overlapping chatter]
‪蟹堡 耶！
-Krabby! [yelling]-One at a time, people.
‪一个一个来
One at a time. [chuckles]
‪章鱼哥‪厨房为何没端出蟹堡王肉饼？
Squidward, why ain't I seeingKrabby Patties
rolling out the service window?
‪-海绵宝宝在哪？‪-我怎么知道？
-Where's SpongeBob?-How should I know?
‪说实在 他不在更好
And, frankly,you won't find me complaining.
Heh-heh!
‪海绵宝宝！你搞什么？
SpongeBob!What's with yer lollygaggin' boy?
‪海绵宝宝？
SpongeBob?
SpongeBob? SpongeBob?
‪快给我出来！这是命令！
Get out here this instant!That's a direct order!
‪我搞不懂 他从未错过任何工作日
I don't get it.He has never missed a workday.
‪蟹堡王肉饼！
[shrieks]
[all chanting] Krabby Patty! Krabby Patty!
‪嘿！我的蟹堡王肉饼呢？
Hey! Where are my Krabby Patties?
‪-我怎么知道？‪-就来了 先生！
-How should I know?-It's coming, sir, it's coming!
‪章鱼哥 快进厨房做出蟹堡王肉饼
Squidward, get in that kitchenand whip up some Krabby Patties.
‪好的 格特鲁德 他那时怎么说的？
All right, Gertrude…Now, what did he say?
‪先激起她的火花
Uh, spark her flints.
‪再轻轻扭动她的开关 好的！
Uh, jiggle her jets.And… oh, yes!
‪“能干的小干锅”
"The Little Griddle Who Could."
‪肉饼说：“但我们刚离开冰箱‪仍冷冰冰的”
"We're fresh from the freezer,"said the little--
‪-蟹老板 我们出了一点问题‪-章鱼哥！
-Mr. Krabs, we've got a---Squidward!
‪快逃命！
Ow! Save… Ow! …yourself!
Oh!
‪海绵宝宝若在的话‪就不会搞得一团乱了
We wouldn't be in this messif SpongeBob was around.
‪海绵宝宝去哪了？
Where is SpongeBob?
[hawk cries]
[both snoring]
[both gasp]
‪我们在哪？
[Patrick] Where are we?
‪我们肯定是在做梦！
We must be dreaming!
‪你真有趣 海绵宝宝
[chortles] You amuse me, SpongeBob.
‪两个人怎么能做同一个梦
Two people can't have the same dream,
‪更别说同时间做同一个梦
let alone be in that same dreamat the same time.
‪这在哲学上站不住脚
That would be philosophically untenable.
‪确实 你提供了形而上学的难题
Indeed. You proffera metaphysical conundrum.
‪等等 我们像聪明人一样对话
Wait, we're talking like smart people.
‪这肯定是一场梦！
This must be a dream!
‪再说 我们在地面上 还呼吸着空气
Plus, we're on the surface and we're…
[inhales] …breathing air, so…
‪没错！
-…yeah!-[gasping]
‪空气？
Air?!
[both laughing]
‪嘿 前方有个小镇！
Hey, town up ahead!
‪“没希望峡谷” 这名字真有趣
[SpongeBob] "Goner Gulch."Ha! That's a funny name.
‪（地狱沙龙）
‪“地狱沙龙”
"The Inferno Saloon."
‪“踏入这里亦放弃所有希望”
"Ye who enter here abandon all hope."
‪我想这个意思其实是在说‪“不得借用厕所”
Guess that's another wayof saying "no public restrooms".
‪有人吗？
Hello?
[voice echoing]
[hawk cries]
‪-奥托 留在附近‪-对 别开走
-Otto, keep it close.-Yeah, don't go anywhere.
‪开走
Go anywhere.
‪能服务您是我的荣幸 你被解雇了
It is my pleasure to serve.You're fired.
‪我们现在该如何找到盖瑞？
Oh! How are we gonna find Gary now?
‪奥托或许只是去停车
-Maybe Otto just went to park.-[both yell]
[both shriek]
‪你好
Hello.
‪你是谁？
[yelps] Who are you?
‪我是一团风滚草 你可以叫我基哥
I am a simple tumbleweed.Call me Sage.
‪-风滚草基哥‪-嘿 风滚草基哥 这名字真不赖
-Sage.-Hey, Sage. Good name.
‪谢谢 我用风滚草打造‪亦是风滚草基哥
Thanks. I'm made out of sage,and I am a sage.
‪这样十分妥当
So it works out pretty well.
‪我是派大星！在凯尔特语中的意思是‪“烤面包机”
-[eye glint chimes]-I'm Patrick!
My name means "toaster" in Celtic.
‪我很确定不是
Pretty sure it doesn't.
‪你们共享的梦隐藏着一个目的‪年轻的寻求者们
This dream you sharehas a hidden purpose, young seekers.
‪原来我们真的在做梦！
Oh! So we are in a dream!
‪而我就是织梦者 我的朋友
And I, friend, am the dream weaver.
‪哦 织梦者
♪ Ohh, dream weaver… ♪
‪哇 你进入到我们的脑里？
Whoa, are you inside our minds right now?
‪-是的 派大星‪-哇！
-Yes, Patrick.-Wow!
‪我是来协助你这趟旅程 海绵宝宝
I am here to help youon your journey, SpongeBob.
‪但首先 你得接受一项挑战
But first, you must accept a challenge.
‪但我只想找出盖瑞并把他带回家
But, I just want to find Garyand bring him home.
‪-你爱盖瑞吗？‪-超过任何事！
-Do you love Gary?-More than anything!
‪那么 年轻的海绵‪你一旦完成这项挑战
And, young sponge,once you meet this challenge
‪就能继续上路 找寻你宝贵的盖瑞
you may pass onto find your precious Gary.
‪-明白了 这说得通了‪-这就说得通了
-Got it. Right.-Oh, right, that makes sense.
[spits]
‪好恶心
Eww.
‪拿着这枚挑战币
[Sage] Take this challenge coin.
‪-挑战币！‪-挑战币！
Challenge coin!
‪这会在你英勇不足时 给予你勇气
It will give you couragewhen bravery is in short supply.
‪-哇！‪-酷毙了！
-Whoa!-Cool!
‪你的挑战位于这道沙龙门后
Now, your challenge lies behindthese saloon doors.
-Let's kill this challenge.-[Sage] Wait, guys!
‪挑战币来了！
[Patrick] Challenge coin coming through!
‪我还没告诉你们挑战是什么！
I didn't give you your challenge!
‪耐心 风滚草基哥 你得有耐心
Patience, Sage. Patience.
Huh.
[piano playing]
‪好酷 是那种古老的钢琴手
Oh, cool.One of those old player pianos.
[laughter]
‪或是那种古老的钢琴手！
-[both yelp]-Or…
one of those old piano players!
[high-pitched cackling]
‪-好可怕的人！‪-好可怕的人！
[both screaming] Scary people!
‪确切地说 那是肉食的牛仔海盗僵尸
Flesh-eating cowboy pirate zombies,to be precise.
‪肉食的牛仔海盗僵尸？
[stuttering] Flesh-eatingcowboy pirate zombies?!
‪这就是你们的挑战
This is your challenge.
‪将这些僵尸从尘世的束缚中解放出来‪并释放他们的灵魂
Free these zombiesfrom their earthly binds
and release their souls.
‪这若不是梦境 我早就吓坏了！
If this weren't a dream,I'd be freaking out right now!
‪对啊！
Oh, yeah!
‪我们在做梦
[giggles] We are in a dream.
-[laughing]-La, la-la, la-la, la, la.
‪听好了 各位！
Okay, everyone!
‪我们是来释放你们被监禁的灵魂
We're here to releaseyour imprisoned souls.
[thunder crashing]
‪那是什么？
What was that?
‪邪恶的暗黑破坏神驾到
Ah, El Diablo the Wicked approaches.
‪暗黑破坏神
♪ El DiabloEl Diablo ♪
‪他是个坏到骨子里的恶人
♪ Very bad man ♪
‪暗黑破坏神？
El Diablo?
‪他是这群僵尸的主人
Master of this zombie crew.
‪-糟糕‪-他听起来坏透了
-Uh-oh.-He sounds bad.
‪祝你们好运
Good luck.
‪派大星 僵尸都向这里蜂拥而至！
Patrick, the zombies are swarming!
‪他们会吃掉我们的脑子！
-They're gonna eat our brains!-[shrieks]
[dance music playing]
‪快跳舞！
♪ Dance! ♪
‪我是史努比老大‪台上台下都同一个风格
♪ Boss Dogg ♪
♪ Even when I'm onI'm off, y'all ♪
‪挑战大王得付出代价‪你们赶紧走吧 是迷路了吧？
♪ Lookin' for the KingIt'll cost y'all ♪
♪ You better leave noware you lost, dawg? ♪
‪僵尸之王 我听到他的脚步声‪传奇的人物来势汹汹
♪ The Zombie KingYeah, I hear him coming ♪
♪ OG ghoul with a thirstFor the run-in ♪
‪你们来错了地方 就等着送死吧
♪ You in the wrong barWrong town ♪
‪真正的胜者即将出现
♪ Got a spot to fill ♪
♪ The real dealComing down that hill ♪
‪啃着你们的脑子做早餐‪灵魂当作小菜
♪ Your brains for breakfast ♪
♪ Soul on the menuMajor checklist ♪
‪食尸鬼和地精 快守护出口吧‪他眼中的怒火 不难发现
♪ Ghouls, goblinsGuard the exit ♪
♪ The fire in his eyesAin't hard to catch it ♪
‪邪恶的暗黑破坏神 我知道这很可怕
♪ El Diablo, the hauntingTaunting veterano ♪
♪ It's scary, I know ♪
‪没希望峡谷事故重重 但别恨这游戏‪谁叫我们都陷入了僵尸行业
♪ The Goner GulchWhere the drama is ♪
♪ But don't hate the gameWe in the zombie biz ♪
‪我们一同舞蹈时就能感受到爱意
-♪ We feel the love ♪-♪ Yes, sir ♪
-♪ When we all dance together ♪-♪ What? What? What? ♪
‪齐心协力
♪ Together ♪
‪我们共同成就了毕生的胜利
♪ We made it, made itUp all life long ♪
‪我们不会就此罢休
♪ We won't stop… ♪
‪暗黑破坏神驾到！
♪ El Diablo is here! ♪
‪快跳舞！我们是最邪恶的团队
-♪ Dance! ♪-♪ We the baddest crew ♪
‪把手高高举起！你还害怕什么？
-♪ Hands high! ♪-♪ What's eating you? ♪
‪我们来势汹汹！
-♪ Us! ♪-♪ We comin' through ♪
‪我们最擅长的就是杀戮！
♪ Killing it is how we do! ♪
‪暗黑破坏神驾到‪嗅一嗅那腐烂的气味
♪ El Diablo's on his waySmell the odor of decay ♪
‪尽情舞动吧‪因为我们最擅长的就是杀戮！
♪ Dance, we came to slay ♪
♪ 'Cause killing itIs how we do! ♪
[gasping]
‪我说过我不在的时候不准跳舞！
What did I tell you aboutdancing when I'm not here?!
‪老大 今天是自由式星期五！
But, boss, it's Freestyle Friday!
‪好的 是我搞错了
Oh. Okay, my bad.
‪我得走了 这里交给你
‪嘿 海绵宝宝？
Hey. Yo, SpongeBob? I got to dip.
Y'all got this.
‪把囚犯带到我办公室
Bring the prisoners to my office.
‪那家伙指的囚犯是什么意思？
Huh. What'd that guy mean by prisoners?
[yelling]
[knife sharpening]
‪你们竟敢踏入该死的鬼城
So, you dare to enterthe ghost town of the damned,
‪还闯进我的恶魔巢穴
barge into my demon's lair…
‪告诉我的僵尸们
telling my zombies…
‪你将释放他们的灵魂
that you're gonna free their souls…
[cackles]
‪好像这一切都不算什么！
like it ain't no thing!
‪暗黑破坏神先生‪好在我们都在梦境中
Well, uh, Mr. Diablo,the good thing is we're in a dream.
‪-这是个共同的梦‪-是的 我们共享的梦境中
-A shared dream.-Right, a shared dream.
‪你实在无需动怒
So there's no need to getall bent out of shape about it.
‪-这一切都不是真实的！‪-因为这只是个梦境
-It's not real!-'Cause it's a dream.
‪是谁告诉你的？那疯狂的灌木家伙？
Who told you that?That crazy bush guy?
‪或许吧
-Uh…-Maybe.
[shrieking]
‪他或许说得对 派大星‪一切感觉好真实
He might be right, Patrick.That felt pretty real.
‪是的 真的好痛
Yeah, that really hurt.
[screaming]
‪快逃！
Run!
‪等一等 派大星
Hang on, Patrick.
‪邪恶的恶魔 快消失！
Foul demon, be gone!
‪那是什么玩意？
What the heck is that?
‪我看起来像是停车收费表吗？
Huh?
What do I look like, a parking meter?
‪但风滚草基哥说过…
But Sage said--
‪投币式洗衣机就在大街上
Coin laundry's right down the street.
[laughs]
‪真是可悲！
That's pathetic!
[yells]
[screams]
‪快远离那些窗帘！
Get away from those curtains!
‪-什么？这些窗帘吗？‪-这些窗帘真不赖
-What? These curtains?-Oh, these are nice curtains.
‪没错 摸起来软绵绵的
Oh, they are. So soft.
-[hissing]-[screams]
‪真是怪异
-That's weird.-[screams]
‪这些窗帘好像发出怪声
These curtains are making a strange sound.
[shrieking]
‪我想是窗帘杆需要抹油了
I think the curtain rod needs some oil.
‪窗帘杆一旦坏掉‪你还不如换一套全新的窗帘
Once the rod goes,you're probably better off
getting a whole new set of curtains.
‪暗黑破坏神先生‪你是否有其他的窗帘…
Oh, Mr. Diablo,do you have any other cur--
Oh!
‪派大星 我们赶紧逃离这里吧！
Patrick, I think we shouldget out of here!
‪嘿 各位！
Hey, everybody!
‪暗黑破坏神先生说谁都别去打扰他
El Diablo says he doesn't wantto be disturbed.
‪是的 他心情有些焦灼
Yeah, he's feeling a little burnt…
[grunts]
‪-好像被烤焦一样‪-再见了！
-…out.-Toodle-oo!
‪-拜拜！‪-不用送了！
-Buh-bye!-See you!
‪保重了！
Take care!
‪谢谢你 海绵宝宝
Thank ye, SpongeBob.
‪我们终于自由了！
We're finally free!
Huh?
‪再见了 伙伴们！
Adiós, mateys!
‪-我们终于自由了‪-祝你们旅途顺利 二位
-Thanks, SpongeBob.-We're finally free.
Good luck on your journey, boys.
‪你知道这意味着什么吗？‪我们通过这项挑战了！
Do you know what this means?
We passed the challenge!
‪我们现在能去找盖瑞了！
Now we can find Gary! Yay!
‪暗黑破坏神
♪ El DiabloEl Diablo ♪
‪（暗黑破坏神办公室）
[yelling]
‪奥托！
Otto!
‪你们好啊 伙伴们
Howdy, partners.
‪等等！不能忘了“勇气”
Wait! Can't forget the "courage."
[growling]
‪是他！
-[Patrick] It's him!-Yikes!
‪-糟糕！‪-奥托 快离开这里！
[Patrick] Come on, Otto. Let's go!
‪奥托 快啊！
[SpongeBob] Come on, come on, Otto!
‪奥托 开快点！
-Step on it, Otto! Go! Go!-Faster! Go faster!
‪奥托 快！
Go, Otto, go!
‪他是个坏到骨子里的恶人
♪ Very bad man ♪
Faster!
‪-醒醒吧 你们的梦被解雇了‪-奥托！
Wake up. Your dream is fired.
‪再快
-[murmuring] Faster-Huh? Oh!
‪太好了！我们又回到海底了
Phew! We're back on the bottom.
‪看吧 派大星？那肯定是一场梦
See, Patrick?It must have been a dream.
‪那更像是一场幻境
[Sage] More of a vision really.
‪-风滚草基哥？‪-你好啊 风滚草基哥
-Sage?-Oh. Hi, Sage.
‪-你们好‪-原来你是真实的
-Hello.-You are real.
‪如你所愿 才能看到你看不到的东西
As real as your desireto see that which you cannot.
‪我看不到的东西是盖瑞
Yeah, well, that whichI cannot see is Gary.
‪我得知道发生了什么事
I got to know what's happening.
‪我将实现你的这个愿望
This wish I grant you.
‪通过神秘的第四维空间
Through the mystical fabricof the fourth dimension,
‪你能在事情正发生的同时‪查看发生了什么事
you may now view what's happening
at the same time as thingsare happening to you.
‪与此同时之窗
Behold. The Window of Meanwhile.
‪与此同时之窗！
The Window of Meanwhile!
‪这有什么用途？
What's it do?
‪这就像并行动作中的视频点播服务
It's like the Video On Demandservice of parallel action.
‪看一看吧
Have a look.
‪嘿 派大星 别挡着
-Whoa…-Hey, Patrick. Down in front.
[Gary purring]
‪看 派大星 他在那里！
Look, Patrick, there he is!
‪他看起来没事 嘿 盖瑞！
Yeah, he looks all right.
-Hey, Gary!-[meows]
‪-他看上去没那么糟糕‪-他看起来挺舒适的！
[SpongeBob] He doesn't look so bad.
He looks pretty comfy!
‪-看来我们无需惊慌‪-没错！
-No reason to panic.-Yeah!
‪-他看上去有被好好照顾‪-看我找到了什么
He looks like he's well taken care of.
‪蜗牛时间到
Look what I found. Snail time.
‪你好啊 宝贝
-[Poseidon] Hello, precious.-[meows]
‪盖瑞？‪希望你不会用尽汁水‪否则下场就跟其他的一样
Gary?
I hope you don't run out of juice,or you'll end up like the others.
‪什么？
[SpongeBob] What?!
[whip cracks]
‪好极了
Oh, yes.
‪-盖瑞！你听得到吗？‪-盖瑞！
-Gary! Gary, hello?-Gary!
‪与此同时之窗不是这样操作的
Okay, the Window of Meanwhiledoesn't really work that way.
‪-盖瑞！快逃离那里！‪-盖瑞！
-Gary, run! Get out of there!-Gary!
‪这不是视频聊天应用程序
It's not a video chat app likeSkype or FaceTime, or anything.
‪-我们得赶紧去那里！盖瑞！‪-这里！盖瑞！
-We got to hurry! Gary!-Over here! Gary!
‪-盖瑞！我们来救你了 盖瑞‪-他完全听不到你说的
[Sage, echoing]Totally can't hear you.
[SpongeBob] Hello!
[bells chime]
‪你好啊 我的老朋友 蟹老板！
Hello, Eugene, old friend!
‪生意如何？
How's business?
[laughs]
‪很糟糕吗？好极了
Bad? Good.
‪餐饮业就是这般残酷‪不是大丰收就是闹饥荒
Well, that's restaurants for you, huh?
Feast or famine. [chuckles]
‪我离题了
But I digress.
‪你不如当个有气度的败者‪乖乖把秘方交出来吧？
Why don't you be a good little loserand hand over the secret formula?
[sighs deeply]
‪拿去吧
Take it. It's yours.
Wha…
‪全都拿走吧
Take it all.
‪等等
Wait…
‪你放弃了？
You're giving up?
‪痞老板 我不奢望你能感同身受
Oh, Plankton…
I wouldn't expect you to understand.
‪但不知何故 少了海绵宝宝
But somehow, without SpongeBob,
‪这里的一切
this whole thing…
‪都变得毫无意义！
just doesn't make sense anymore!
‪你不能这样‪我耗上毕生的事业就为这一刻
You can't do that.
I've spent my entire careerwaiting for this moment
‪你却像只泄气的鲸鱼一蹶不振？
and you roll over like a harpooned whale?
‪我不会让你如此夺走我的复仇大计！
I won't let you rob me of my vengeance!
‪代我问候你美丽的妻子
Give my regards to your lovely wife.
[sniffles, moans]
Huh.
‪这感觉
This doesn't, uh…
‪没有想象中雀跃
feel quite as good as, uh…
‪太好了 我赢了
Yay, I won.
‪恭喜 您已抵达目的地
[Otto] Congratulations.
You have arrived at your destination.
‪失落的大西洋城！
[SpongeBob]The Lost City of Atlantic City!
‪好漂亮
[Patrick] It's pretty.
‪当心 年轻的寻求者们
Beware, young seekers.
‪眼前的一切都是扭曲的
All is distortion.
‪你们一不小心就会被失落之城‪诱导到她善变的拥抱中
If you aren't careful,The Lost City will draw you
into her fickle embrace,
‪她会用眼花缭乱的景象干扰你‪诱惑你参与她各式各样的机遇游戏
blind you with her dazzling distractions
and tempt you with herfleeting games of chance.
‪更别忘了你们来此的目的
don't lose focusand don't forget why you came here.
‪我们懂得该怎么做
‪-忘记？才怪‪-谢了 风滚草基哥
-Don't forget. Good one.-Thanks, Sage-meister.
‪是的 风滚草基哥‪你一路来都很有智慧
-I think we got this.-Yeah, Sage.
I mean, you've been pretty goodup until now, but,
‪但别忘了 我爱盖瑞超过全世界！
I love Gary more than anythingin the whole world!
‪-我们来此的目的是把他带走‪-好的
And we came here to get him back.
[Sage] Okay.
‪我才不担心我们会失去专注力
I wouldn't worry about uslosing any focus.
‪天啊
Oh, boy.
‪我们得专注 宝贝
We got focus to burn, baby--
[both] Whoa!
‪-棉花糖！‪-冰淇淋！
-Cotton candy!-Ice cream!
‪吉拿棒！
Churros!
["Livin' La Vida Loca" playing]
-Oh! Oh! Oh!-Yay!
Yumm!
[screams]
[munching]
[yelling]
‪你们好啊！
What's up?
‪（赌场）
‪好酷 这里可以用真钱‪换取这些圆形小塑胶
Isn't it cool how they let youtrade in your real money
for these little plastic circles?
‪我好爱钱！
[Otto] I love money!
‪赌场都有股魔幻的魅力
Casinos are magical.
‪-你不介意我把这个放下吧 先生？‪-你爱放哪就放哪
Would you mind if I put this down, sir?
Place it wherever you like.
‪放在L的位置上
Just put it on L.
‪-派大星 那不是字母L 是数字7‪-数字7跟字母L一样？好奇怪
Patrick, that's not an L, that's a seven.
Seven starts with an L?That's weird.
‪七号！
Seven!
‪更多的圆形小塑胶！
More plastic circles!
‪-你们是谁？‪-我们是你们的随行人员
-Who are you guys?-[all] We're your entourage.
[all] ♪ Upside, inside out ♪
♪ She's livin' la vida loca ♪
‪请下注
Place your bets.
‪来吧 七号！
Come on, seven!
‪幸运的七号！大赢家！
Lucky seven! Winner!
[cheering]
♪ Living la vida loca! ♪
‪真是疯狂的人生！
‪七号！七号！七号！
Seven! Seven! Seven!
‪七号 七号 七号
[Patrick chanting] Seven. Seven. Seven.
[all cheering]
‪-嘿 派大星！‪-什么事 海绵宝贝？
-Hey, Patrick!-What's up, Spongey-Dawg?
‪-我把钱都输光了‪-我也是！
-I lost all my money.-Me, too!
[entourage groans]
[laughing]
‪（就在今夜！唱片骑士派大星）
[humming]
‪狂欢的人儿！
-[SpongeBob coughing]-Party people!
[exclaiming]
‪大家都到哪去了？
Oh. Where is everybody?
[groans, coughing]
‪我感觉自己像是吞下了一个海胆
I feel like I swallowed a sea urchin.
‪我也是
Me, too. [coughs]
‪嘿 我真的吞下海胆！
Hey, I did swallow a sea urchin!
‪看吧
Well, well, well.
‪风滚草基哥老大！‪见到你真好 朋友！
Sagester! Good to see ya, pal!
‪做得真是好 各位
Nice work, boys.
‪你们把我的金玉良言全都抛在脑后
Way to take my pearls of wisdomand flush them down the toilet.
‪糟糕 等等 我们是否…
Oh, no. Wait, did we…?
‪没提高警惕并完全失去专注力？
Lose focus like I told you not to?
‪专注力？
Focus? Huh.
‪让我重整你们的思绪
Let me jangle your minds.
‪你们来此是为夺回失去的东西
You came here to get backsomething you lost.
‪我…
-Uh…-Hm.
‪一样你非常爱的东西
Something you love.
‪-盖瑞！‪-盖瑞！
[both] Gary!
‪是的 盖瑞
Yeah, Gary.
‪说实在 被困在风滚草已经够难受了
Seriously, it's hard enoughbeing stuck in a tumbleweed…
‪派大星 我们得去找盖瑞！
Patrick, we got to find Gary!
‪但应对你们让我想把自己点燃
…but dealing with you two makes mewant to light myself on fire.
‪风滚草基哥朋友
Sage, buddy.
‪我们能否再看与此同时之窗‪找出盖瑞在哪？
Can we please look intothe Window of Meanwhile
one more time to see where Gary is?
‪不 这不是随选服务
No, it's not an on-demand service.
‪尤其不适合在自己呕吐物中‪昏睡一整夜的人
And especially not for people who pass outand sleep in their own vomit all night.
‪那不是呕吐物 是口水
It's not vomit. It's drool.
[grumbling]
‪你们很幸运能在这里醒来
Fortunately for you,you woke up right here.
‪这里是波塞冬宫殿的门口
On the steps of Poseidon's Palace.
‪-哇‪-哇
-[SpongeBob] Whoa.-[Patrick] Wow.
‪振作起来 快去！
Now get it together. Go!
‪好的 盖瑞 我们来救你了！
All right, Gary. We're coming for ya!
Almost there, Gary.
They're just giving these thingsaway at the grocery store.
‪好主意 朋友
Good call, buddy.
‪帅哥借过！
Hot stuff coming through!
‪看看这地方 派大星
Get a load of this place, Patrick.
‪你好
Hello.
‪我们求见波塞冬国王殿下
We would like an audiencewith His Majesty King Poseidon.
‪没问题 有两位俗人要见波塞冬‪让我查查看 你们想得美
Oh, sure. Let me check.Two rubes to see Poseidon. No.
‪（倒车）
[both yelling]
‪-嘿 兄弟 我们是蓝鳍组合‪-好的 这里请
Hey, dude. We're the Blue Fin Group.
Of course. Right this--
Hey!
‪不得进入！
[yelling]
‪（舞台入口）
-[band finishing tune]-Hey, hey, hey!
‪我是蒂芙尼哈多克 我只是来玩乐的
I'm Tiffany Haddockand I'm here just for the halibut.
-Ha-ha-ha!-[rimshot]
-[laughter]-Whoo-hoo!
‪好的 我们下一组表演者…
All right then.
Our next performers are gonna knock--
-[grunting]-[crash]
‪（水色房）
[Poseidon laughs]
‪波塞冬？
Poseidon?
‪我们见到国王了
We are getting an audience with the King.
‪来吧 请开始表演！
Well, let's have it. Perform, please!
‪嘿 阿卡哇卡玛卡米亚是只河豚鱼
♪ Hey! Aka Waka Maka Mia ♪
-♪ Was a puffer fish ♪-[farts]
‪想变得大过河豚鱼 是他唯一的愿望
♪ Being bigger than a pufferWas his only wish ♪
‪他于是大口喘气大口呼气‪圆滚滚的膨胀
♪ And so he huffed, he puffed ♪
-♪ He billowed and he blew ♪-[Gary meows]
‪-盖瑞！‪-盖瑞！
[both] Gary!
[meows]
‪盖瑞 我来了 朋友！
Gary, I'm coming, buddy!
-[diner shouts]-[meows]
‪抱歉 请让开！
Excuse me. Sorry. My bad. Whoop.
‪抱歉
Sorry. Whoa!
‪不好意思 波塞冬国王殿下
Hi, there! Excuse me, King Poseidon, sire.
‪你对盖瑞有些误解
There's been a misunderstandingabout Gary.
‪盖瑞？
-Gary?-[meows]
‪-盖瑞‪-盖瑞？
-Gary.-Gary?
‪你正用来涂抹脸的那只蜗牛
The snail that you're rubbingall over your face right now.
‪胡说八道 再说‪这只蜗牛的名字叫弗雷德
Nonsense. Besides,this snail's name is Fred.
‪“弗雷德”？你替盖瑞改名？
"Fred?" You renamed Gary?
‪-弗雷德‪-盖瑞
-Fred.-Gary.
‪-弗雷德！‪-盖瑞！
-Fred! Fred!-Gary! Gary!
-Fred!-Gary!
‪弗雷德！
Fred!
‪捉住他们！
Seize them!
‪盖瑞！
[SpongeBob] Gary!
Gary!
‪但盖瑞爱我！我也爱他！
But Gary loves me! And I love him.
[meows sadly]
‪呀呼！
[Sandy] Yeehaw!
‪前进！
Incoming!
[laughs]
Whoa!
‪火箭乖乖
Good rockets.
‪海绵宝宝？
-[knocking on door]-SpongeBob?
‪准备出发了 小子 我们去骑火箭
Get yer co-pilot goggles, dude,
'cause we're goin' sleddin'!
‪海绵宝宝？
SpongeBob?
‪你在吗？
You in here?
‪海绵宝宝？
SpongeBob?
[yelps]
‪海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob!
‪这真奇怪
Huh. That's weird.
‪这里有古怪
Something's fishy around here.
‪快说 你们对海绵宝宝做了什么？
All right, what'd y'all do with SpongeBob?
‪我们不知道他去了哪 珊迪‪他已经很多天没来过了
We don't know where he is, Sandy.
Hasn't been here in days. [screams]
‪少跟我耍花样 头足类动物
Don't you play coy with me, cephalopod.
‪还有你这个节肢动物！从实招来
-And you, arthropod!-[shrieks]
‪他在哪？被捆绑在地下室？‪还是被塞进你的后备箱？
Start talking. Where is he?
Tied up in the basement?Stuffed in your trunk?
‪我是不可能会伤害那小子的‪他的缺席教会我很多事
Nay, I could never harm the lad.
His absence has taught me that much.
‪我指的不只是被亏损的钱财‪他的离去让我难以适应
And I'm not just talking aboutthe money I'm losing with him gone.
[both] Hmm…
‪好吧 有一半原因是因为亏损钱
Okay, fifty percenttalking about the money
‪另一半是因为我真的想念那小子
and fifty percent talking aboutI truly miss the boy.
Aw.
‪我很不愿承认‪但少了他一切都不同了
I hate to admit it, but thingsjust aren't the same without him.
‪不可否认 我们都需要海绵宝宝
There's no denying it. We need SpongeBob.
‪你们没想过他此刻‪或许需要我们的帮忙？
Did anyone ever stop to thinkthat he might need us?
‪我是鲈鱼珀金斯‪在失落的大西洋城为您报导
This is Perch Perkins coming to youfrom The Lost City of Atlantic City.
‪我此刻位于波塞冬宫殿‪和赌场外的地皮上
I'm standing on the strip outside
‪今晚有两名嫌疑犯因刑事拘留被带走
Poseidon's Palace and Casino,where two suspects have been
‪他们企图夺走皇家蜗牛
-taken into custody tonight…-[gasping]
…following an attempt on the Royal Snail.
‪这两名嫌犯‪海绵和海星冒充舞台演出
The sponge and sea star wereimpersonating a lounge act
‪企图夺走波塞冬最宝贵的软体动物
when they made an attempton Poseidon's prize mollusk.
[meows]
The suspects' vehicle was apprehendedafter a high-speed chase.
‪蟹老板 奥托在哪？
Mr. Krabs. What happened to Otto?
‪他自动休假！
Well, he took an automated vacation!
‪在相关报导中‪波塞冬宫殿下令御前演出
In a related story, Poseidon's Palace
‪周五晚在水色房处决嫌犯
presents a command performance,featuring the execution
of the suspects in the Aqua Roomthis Friday night.
‪处决嫌犯？鱼身保护令法则呢？
[spits] Execution of the suspects?
What happened to habeas swordfish?
‪这将是充满欢乐的家庭活动‪由凯尔皮G做开场演出
It's a fun-filled family event,with opening act Kelpy G.
‪只限一场演出 门票仍在出售中
One performance only,tickets still available.
[both gasp]
‪-我们得去救他们！‪-立即启程
-We've got to go help them!-We embark immediately.
‪不好意思
Excuse me.
‪我能跟着去吗？
Can I tag along?
‪痞老板？这事跟你有什么关联？
Plankton?
What have you got to do with this?
‪我…
[stammering] I… I…
‪我或许有那么一丁点的责任
I might have had a teensy-weensyhand in a very--
‪好的 我们上车再说
Yeah, yeah,we'll hear about it in the car.
‪章鱼哥先生 你也一同去吗？
Mr. Squidward, are ya coming?
‪哈！你想得美
Ha! Fat chance.
‪休想要我错过任何一场‪凯尔皮G的演出 算我一份
Fat chance I'd missa Kelpy G performance. I'm in.
‪前往蟹堡王肉饼汽车！
To the Pattymobile!
‪什么？我们得开这台老爷车？
What, this old tub?
‪别用外表来衡量‪蟹堡王肉饼汽车 章鱼哥
Never judge a Pattymobileby its bun, Squidward.
‪我们出发吧！
Let's light this puppy!
[crank squeaking]
‪（点火）
[Mr. Krabs cackling]
‪呀呼！
[Sandy] Yeehaw!
[all exclaiming]
‪我的妈呀！
Mommy!
[long, somber musical note playing]
[chuckles]
[playing higher note]
‪海绵宝宝？
Huh? SpongeBob?
‪你没事吧？
Are you okay?
‪朋友 我对此感到抱歉
Hey, buddy. Sorry about this.
‪这不是你的错 派大星‪你一直都是最真诚的朋友
[sniffling] It's not your fault, Patrick.
You've been a true friend this whole time.
‪你对我的友谊永不动摇 只不过…
Never wavered, never faltered. It's just…
‪我失败了！
I failed, that's all!
‪我再也看不见无辜的小盖瑞了
And I'll never seeinnocent little Gary again.
‪哦 我的心碎了！
Oh, my heart is broken!
‪别这样
-[crying]-Oh, come on now.
‪振作起来 一切还未结束 海绵宝宝
Buck up. It's not over yet, SpongeBob.
‪我感觉这早已成定局了 这糟透了
It sure feels over. And crappy.
‪别忘了每个钱币都有正反两面
Just saying there'stwo sides to every coin.
‪派大星 这关钱币什么事…‪等等 你刚刚说的是钱币？
Oh, Patrick, what does a coin have to--
Wait, did you just say "coin"?
‪我吗？好像不是吧
Me? Uh, don't think so.
-[mooing noise]-[giggles]
‪你确实有提到钱币！
You did. You said "coin"!
‪我不太记得了
-Not remembering that exactly.-[makes telephone noise]
‪你还不明白吗 派大星？‪我们获救了！
Oh, don't you see, Patrick? We're saved!
‪我接电话了
I said hello.
‪派大星 不见了！
Patrick, it's gone!
‪那又怎样？那枚挑战币很重要吗？
Meh. Was the challenge coinreally that useful?
‪喂？
Hello?
‪真是的！愚蠢的恶作剧来电者
Oh! Stupid prank callers.
‪嘿 等一等
Hey, wait a sec.
‪我把那交给你保管 还记得吗？
I gave it to you, remember?For safe keeping.
‪不记得
No.
‪拜托 那不过是昨晚的事！‪我们当时在玩掷骰子
Come on, it was last night!We were at the crappie tables.
‪赢家！快下注吧
[croupier] Winner! Place your bets.
‪拜托 七号！七号！
Come on, seven! Come on, seven!Come on, seven!
‪是你！
You!
‪你把我的挑战币输掉了！
You gambled away my challenge coin!
‪你因为一个愚蠢的赌注‪毁掉我们整个任务！
You wrecked our entire missionwith one stupid bet!
‪那还不是因为你一直对我说
Well, only after you kept saying…
‪快下注 派大星！快下注！
Let it ride, Patrick! Let it ride!
‪但是 海绵宝宝
-Whoo!-But, SpongeBob…
‪要是你明天需要用挑战币‪来召唤勇气呢？
What if you needthe challenge coin tomorrow
to help you summon your courage?
‪明天是留给弱者的！
Tomorrow is for weenies!
Whoo! [laughing]
‪明天已来临 看看谁才是弱者
Well, it's tomorrow and guesswho's the weenie.
[huffs]
‪我真是
I… can't…
‪无法相信你！
believe you!
‪你无法相信我？开什么玩笑？
You can't believe me?Are you serious right now?
‪你或许可以相信即将发生的
Well! Maybe you can believe this.
‪因为我走了！
I'm out of here!
‪别再回来！
And don't come back!
‪别担心 我不会的！
Oh, don't worry, I won't!
‪-好极了！‪-永不回头！
-Good!-Ever!
‪-好啊！‪-好棒！
-Fine!-Super!
‪嘿 你们这两个失败者
Hey, losers.
‪你好啊 风滚草基哥
Oh, hey, Sage.
‪风滚草基哥 你来得正好‪猜猜是谁把我的挑战币输掉
Sage, glad you're here.
Guess who gambled away my challenge coin.
‪猜猜是谁把自己的问题都怪罪于他人
Guess who blames everyone elsefor his troubles.
‪够了！
Enough!
‪我有说过你们是我担任精神向导‪最糟糕的史诗英雄吗？
Did I mention you arethe worst epic heroes
for whom I have ever been a spirit guide?
‪-我们今早好像有谈到‪-好像是的
Um, I think we went over thatthis morning.
I believe we did, yeah.
[sighs]
‪海绵宝宝 那枚钱币只是一个象征
SpongeBob, the coin was just a symbol.
‪你所寻的英勇来自你内心‪而非那枚钱币
The courage you seek is inside you,
not in the coin.
‪这会在你英勇不足时 给予你勇气
And it will come to youin your hour of need.
‪此刻不正是我英勇不足之时？
But isn't this my hour of need?
‪哦 不是的 情况会变得更糟
[laughs] Oh, no.
It gets way worse.
‪再见了！
Bye!
‪-更糟？‪-那家伙说还会更糟糕
-Worse?-Dude said way worse.
‪准备好囚犯
[scatting] Prepare the prisoners.
‪他指的应该不是我们吧
Oh, that couldn't be for us.
‪让你们受苦的时刻到了‪不 是让你们受表扬的时刻
It's your big moment to fry…I mean, shine.
‪那是冲着我们来的 派大星！‪我们死定了！
[gasps] It is for us, Patrick!We're gonna die!
‪我就是这样把海绵宝宝引出比奇堡的
[Plankton] And that's how I got SpongeBob
out of Bikini Bottom. [giggles]
‪-你真是邪恶！‪-等等 这听起来真不错
-Why, that's monstrous!-Wait, that sounds good.
‪我们专注于救人计划吧
Let's just focus on the plan.
‪我们即将抵达失落的大西洋城
[Mr. Krabs] We're approachingThe Lost City of Atlantic City.
‪让一让！
-Make way there, make way!-[pedestrians exclaim]
Oh!
Eww.
‪“海绵与海星的华丽死刑”？
"Sponge and Star Execution Extravaganza"?
‪没时间了！
No time to lose!
‪女士先生们 欢迎来到水色房
Woop, woop, woop! Ladies and gentlefish,
welcome to the Aqua Room, y'all.
‪海底下最盛大的演出
The greatest show underwater.
[playing upbeat tune]
‪我的拥护者们
[Tiffany] My groupies and groupers…
‪-我们爱你 蒂芙尼！‪-来点欢呼声吧！
-We love you, Tiffany!-Yeah holler at your girl!
‪各位准备好被娱乐了吗？
Are you ready to be entertained?
‪我听不见 你准备好被娱乐了吗？
Hmm? I can't hear you.
Are you ready to be entertained?
[laughs]
‪好的 让我们见见参赛者
All right, then,let's meet the contestants.
‪在这个角落的是海绵和海星
In this corner, a sponge and a star…
‪（喝倒彩）
[crowd hissing, booing]
‪在这一角落是国王殿下的代表
And in this corner,representing His Majesty the King,
‪波塞冬国王的大臣！
Poseidon's very own Chancellor!
Now drum roll, maestro.
‪大家一同欢迎残酷无情‪挥舞斧子的疯子
-[drum roll]-Put your fins together
for the duke of the dirty deed,
‪执行过无数次死刑的伯爵
the earl of execution,
that axe-wielding maniac…
‪雷默特！
…oh, yeah, Lemont! [laughing]
[crowd chanting] Lamont! Lamont! Lamont!
‪（死刑台）
Oh, I love me some Lemont.
‪哦 我好爱雷默特 他好有力量
Mm, mm, mm. He's so strong.
[both gulping]
‪女士先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
‪让我们用爵士乐的瞬间‪来纪念即将完蛋的人
with a moment of smooth jazz
in memory of the soon-to-be-goners,
‪有请凯尔皮G
I give you Kelpy G.
[playing "My Heart Will Go On"]
‪派大星 我感到很愧疚‪这一切都是我连累你的
Oh, Patrick, I feel terrible.
I dragged you into this whole mess.
‪没关系 海绵宝宝‪我已对控方提出了抗辩！
It's okay, SpongeBob.
I made a plea deal with the prosecution!
‪那就好…等等 你做了什么？
Oh, that's good-- Wait, you did what?
‪我只需要做的是…
All I have to do is, uh… oh, yeah!
‪“向被告提出有罪证供”
"Bring incriminating evidenceagainst the defendant."
‪派大星 我就是被告
-[laughs]-Patrick, I'm the defendant.
‪是你吗？
You are? Oh.
[song ends]
‪开始审判！
Let the proceedings begin!
‪法官阁下 我想呈上证据‪海蜗牛一只
Your Honor, I would liketo enter into evidence
‪他的名字是弗雷德
one sea snail. Name: Fred.
[Gary meows]
‪我对你只想说一句岂有此理！
‪盖瑞！
-Gary!-How dare you!
That's about all I can say.
‪你竟敢闯入这里
How dare you come here
‪到我们尊贵君主的庇护所
to the sanctuary of our revered sovereign,
‪意图夺走他的命脉
to rob him of his very lifeblood,
‪他的绝世美貌
his adorable good looks.
‪继续说下去
[laughs] Go on.
‪你真是好大的胆子
How indeed dare you.
‪有罪！
-[crowd jeering]-Guilty!
‪雷默特！雷默特！雷默特！
[crowd chanting] Lemont! Lemont! Lemont!
-[roars]-[gasping]
[grunts]
‪等等！
Hold it!
‪庭上 请允许我为海绵宝宝做出辩解
If it please the court,
I'd like to say somethingin SpongeBob's defense.
‪不被庭上允许‪请坐下 头戴鱼缸的松鼠
It does not please the court.
Sit down, squirrel with fishbowl on head.
‪但是 法官阁下‪有辩解才能让演出更为精彩
But, sire, a strong defensemakes for a better show.
‪你们说对吗 观众们？
Isn't that right, audience?
[cheering]
‪好吧 我允许
[grunting]
All right, all right! I'll allow it.
‪谢谢你 法官阁下
[Sandy] Thank you, Your Honor.
‪女士先生们 海绵宝宝一直‪都在我身边支持鼓励我
Ladies and gentlemen,
SpongeBob has always been there for me.
‪这得一路回溯到那个夏令营
Even going all the way backto summer camp.
‪我们也是在那时相识的
In fact, that's where we all met.
[children yelling, laughing]
[chattering, laughing]
‪我…
I'm…
Ow! Ah! Ooh! Ooh!
‪准备好了！
ready!
‪（珊瑚夏令营）
‪看看这些酷毙的活动！
Look at all the cool activities!
‪露营和划独木舟
Camping. Canoeing.
‪骑行海马！
Seahorse-back riding!
‪拔河比赛和观赏鲸鱼
Tug-of-war. Whale watching.
‪别看了行吗？
Do you mind?
‪杂耍比赛和收缩足球赛！
Juggling contests. Shrink-wrap soccer!
[Sandy] Whoo-hoo!
[SpongeBob] Whoa!
‪嘿 你们这些海洋生物！让开！
Hey, y'all critters of the sea!Look out below!
‪我是来自德克萨斯州的珊迪
I'm Sandy Cheeks from Texas.
‪嗨 珊迪 我是海绵宝宝
Hi, Sandy. I'm SpongeBob.
‪很高兴认识你
Pleased to meet ya.
‪在德克萨斯州‪每个人都穿宇航服吗？
Does everybody wear spacesuits in Texas?
‪若想探访你们‪这些海洋生物时就得穿上
They do if they want to visityou underwater critters.
‪我们都在海面上呼吸空气
We all breathe air on the surface.
‪这是我们合成氧气的方式
It's just our way of synthesizing oxygen.
‪就犹如你们在水底一样
Same as you do with water.
‪哇 你是科学家吗？
Whoa. Are you a scientist?
‪才不是 我是一只松鼠
Naw, I'm just a squirrel.
‪我当不成科学家‪即便那算是我的梦想
I can't be a scientist.
Even though it's kind of my dream.
‪珊迪 你快收回这句话！‪只要是你想做的一定办得到！
Sandy Cheeks, you take that back!
I bet you can do anything.
‪真的吗？哇
Really? Wow.
‪我也能成为科学家？
Me a scientist?
‪科学
-[roaring]-[male voice] Science.
‪你真有趣 小家伙
[giggles] You're a hoot, little dude.
‪我也很想生活在水底‪在有一棵树的玻璃圆顶里
I'd be just as likely to live down here
in a glass dome with a tree in it.
‪凡事无绝对！
-Ha-ha!-You never know!
[laughing]
-Ow.-[laughs]
Ow.
‪他是第一个告诉我
[Sandy] He's the one that told me,
‪不论我是谁 出身如何
no matter who I was or where I came from,
‪我都该追逐我的梦想
I should follow my dream.
‪这就是一个真正的朋友 各位
That's a friend, people.
‪这也是为何在我眼里
And that's why, in my eyes…
‪海绵宝宝不可能是罪犯
SpongeBob is no criminal.
‪他是踏入海底最美好的小家伙
He's the best little fella
to ever walk the sea bottom. And that's…
‪这就是我的感受
That's just how I feel about it. So…
‪恳请大家不要伤害他
Please, don't hurt him.
[all] Aww…
‪这家伙触犯了法律！
This man broke the law!
[all gasping]
and accept the factthat somebody stole your snail."
‪但根据这只海星的观点
Well, in this sea star's opinion,
‪这些法律都应该被触犯‪而海绵宝宝也证实了这一点！
those laws should be brokenand SpongeBob is proof of it!
‪他唯一犯下的罪行
All he's guilty of
‪就是有毅力试图营救一个朋友
is having the fortitudeto try and rescue a friend.
‪我又怎么会知道呢？
[meows]
How do I know?
‪我与他初次相识时‪不过是木头上一个孤独的物体
Oh, I was just a lonely bump on a log
when I first met him.
[crying]
‪嗨 我的名字是…
-Hi, my name---[wailing]
Hi, my name--
‪你好啊 我叫海绵宝宝‪你叫什么名字？
Hello my name is SpongeBob,what's your name?
‪我叫派派派大星
I'm Pa-Pa-Patrick.
‪你为何哭泣 派派派大星？
Why are you crying, Pa-Pa-Patrick?
‪我好想家
I'm homesick.
‪那确实是个充分的理由
Well, that's a pretty good reason.
‪或许你需要的是一个朋友
-Maybe all you need is a friend.-[wailing]
‪我没有任何朋友！
I don't have any friends!
‪-你现在有朋友了‪-真的？
-Well, you've got one now.-Really?
‪-那是谁？‪-是我！
-Who is it?-It's me!
‪-你是认真的？‪-当然 走吧！
-Do you mean it?-Of course. Come on!
‪这个贴心的小海绵
[Patrick] That sweet little sponge
‪拯救了这个可悲的小海星
rescued this miserable little sea star.
‪自那天起 我们的友谊一如往昔‪法官阁下
And things haven't changedthat much today, Your Honor.
[sniffles]
‪我说的全都发自内心 朋友
My heart, buddy.
‪我不喜欢海绵宝宝
-[chains rattle]-I don't like SpongeBob.
‪事实上 我十分憎恨他
In fact, I revile him.
-Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!-[loud thud]
‪我也是在夏令营认识这个傻子
Anyway, I, too, met this nabobin summer camp.
‪那记忆清晰如昨天
I remember it like it was yesterday.
‪那是我的重大夜晚‪珊瑚营的年度才艺秀
It was my big night.
The Annual Camp Coral Talent Show.
[playing "Flight of the Bumblebee"]
‪一等奖是令人垂涎的坎比奖
And first prize was the covetedCampy Award.
‪谢谢你 莱瑞 大家别忘了投票
Thank you, Larry.
Remember, people, don't forget to vote.
[vocalizing]
‪对我来说 那座奖杯是属于我的
[Squidward] As far as I was concerned,
the trophy was as good as mine.
‪嘿 章鱼哥
-Hey, Squidward---Bup, bup, bup, bup.
‪别吵 我在预备赛事
Quiet. I'm in pregame right now.
‪我得赢得奖项
I've got an award to win.
[whistling]
[saws buzzing]
-[belches]-♪ La, la-la-la, loo! ♪
♪ La-la ♪
‪阿卡哇卡玛卡米亚是只河豚鱼
♪ Aka Waka Maka MiaWas a puffer fish ♪
[fart noise]
‪奖项是属于我的
-[applause]-[laughs] The Campy is mine.
[lilting music plays]
‪我把天籁般的单簧管演奏呈现给观众
[Squidward] I bathed the audience
with the sounds of myheavenly clarinet playing.
[playing off-key notes]
[retching]
[record scratches]
‪谢谢你 章鱼哥 那真是美妙
Thank you, Squidward. Just lovely.
‪谢谢
Thank you, thank you.
[murmuring]
‪奖项属于…
And the Campy goes to…
‪给我吧
[young Squidward] I'll take that.
‪海绵宝宝和派大星
-…SpongeBob and Patrick!-Huh?
‪不！
-[audience cheering]-No! No! No!
[all gasping]
‪这是不可能的！我的妈呀！
This isn't happening!
[crying] No! Mommy!
‪我被夺走属于我的东西
[Squidward] I was robbed.
‪我从此再也不弹奏单簧管了
And never to play the clarinet again.
[crying quietly] No…
‪-章鱼哥！‪-走开！
-Squidward!-Go away!
‪我和派大星跟其中一位辅导员聊天‪接下来肯定会让你意想不到
Patrick and I were, um,
talking to one of the counselorsand guess what?
‪他们搞错了 坎比奖其实该归你！
There was a big mistake and youactually won the Campy Award!
‪没错
That's right. Yup.
‪-我吗？‪-你的选票占压倒性多数
-I… I did?-In a landslide.
‪他们会算错票数还真是怪异‪但也不是没可能
Hmm.
So weird they would'vemiscounted like that.
-But I guess it's possible---[both] Yay!
‪-做得好 章鱼哥‪-你比谁都实至名归
-Nice work, Squidward.-No one deserves it more.
‪哇‪你也一定要继续弹奏这个
Wow.
And don't ever stop playing this.
‪我的单簧管
My clarinet.
‪我真的做到了！
Look at me. I really did it!
‪太好了！
Yay!
‪这也是为何 我虽然讨厌海绵宝宝
Which is why, even thoughI can't stand SpongeBob…
‪但在同时
but at the same time, well…
‪我也爱他
I love him.
‪我对他爱恨难分
-[gasps]-I love him
-and I hate him.-Oh.
‪他就像加了盐巴的雪糕
He's like ice cream with salt on it,
‪因为他贴心却也很烦人
because he's sweet and super annoying.
‪他的人很好
He's nice and
‪却也令人受不了的讨厌！
nails-on-chalkboard annoying!
‪好吧 他大部分时候都非常讨人厌
Okay, fine, he's mostlysuper freaking annoying.
‪但这叽喳的讨厌鬼
But, this little nattering noodge…
‪是我的朋友
is my friend.
‪他罪不该死
And he doesn't deserve to die.
[meows]
[playing melodic tune]
‪若庭上允许的话 我将开始我的说辞
I'll be saying my piece now,if it be pleasing the court.
‪我可以告诉各位‪海绵宝宝是如何改变我的人生
[clears throat]I suppose I could stand up here
and tell you howSpongeBob changed me life.
‪但我不会对大家倾诉
But, I won't.
‪我或许也能分享他对我的启发
I might even speakabout how he inspired me
‪我当时是一个潦倒的餐饮车摊贩
when I was just a small-time vendorwith a broken-down luncheonette.
‪但我也不想多说
But I won't.
to start up me own restaurant.
‪你有一天应该自己开餐馆
You should open upyour own restaurant, someday.
‪售卖蟹堡王肉饼闻名的蟹堡王！
The Krusty Krab, made famousby me delicious Krabby Patties!
‪顺道一提 周三有买一送一活动‪请把这个传下去
Two-for-one Wednesdays,by the way. Pass these around.
Nay, you'll hear none such praise from me.
‪因为这不足以显示他的美好
Because it wouldn't do him full justice.
‪这小子的善良远远超出这一切
It wouldn't begin to describethe size of the lad's heart.
‪他的心很大很大
Which is huge.
‪他也将其投入所有事 像他的烹饪…
And he puts that heartinto everything he does.
The cooking…
‪-上菜！‪-打扫
-Order up!-…cleaning…
‪以及烹煮美味可口的蟹堡王肉饼
…serving up the deliciousKrabby Patties.
‪但有趣的是
But that's the funny thing.
‪我曾以为我的蟹堡王肉饼秘方
I used to thinkme secret Krabby Patty formula
‪是让我迈向成功的原因
was also the secret to me success.
‪还有 我们从11点供应早餐‪周末12点起
We serve breakfast till 11,by the way, 12 on weekends.
‪海绵宝宝来替我工作之后
It wasn't until SpongeBobcame to work for me
‪我才意识到 原来秘方
that I realized the formula
‪不只是材料成分表和烹煮方式
is more than just a list of ingredients
and flavor-capturing methods.
‪那已远远超出一个被私心霸占的食谱
It's more than a jealouslyguarded recipe.
‪真正的秘方
The real secret formula
‪就坐在那里
is sitting right here.
‪那就是海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants.
Aww…
‪做好准备
Get ready.
‪音乐大师？
Ahem! Maestro?
[playing dramatic intro]
‪一个秘方就犹如一个食谱
♪ A formula is somethingLike a recipe ♪
‪一个食谱就犹如一个计划
♪ A recipe is somethingLike a plan ♪
‪带有元素和测量‪全由一双稳固的手灌入
♪ With elements and measurements ♪
♪ All mixed together by a steady hand ♪
‪但你得当心 否则肯定会伤心
♪ But careful you must beOr you'll be sad you see ♪
‪若在其中缺少了灵魂
♪ If somehow in the mixIt has no soul ♪
‪能让这美好酱汁升华的唯一材料‪究竟是什么？
♪ So what's the one ingredient ♪
♪ That turns this awesome sauceTo liquid gold? ♪
‪让我来告诉你吧！
I'll tell ya!
‪秘方的秘密其实就是你
♪ The secret to the formulaIs you, you ♪
‪就是你
♪ You, you ♪
‪在我茶里的蜜糖其实就是你
♪ The honey in my tea, you knowIs you, you ♪
-♪ The bubbles in the boil ♪-[shrieking]
‪缺一不可的香精油
♪ The one essential oilIt's true ♪
‪秘方的秘密其实就是你
♪ The secret to the formulaIs you, you ♪
‪就是你
‪海绵宝宝！
-SpongeBob!-♪ You, you ♪
‪在辽阔的海底世界
♪ What in the wide watery world ♪
‪若少了你会是如何？
♪ Would it be like without you? ♪
‪秘方的秘密其实就是你
♪ The secret to the formulaIs you, you ♪
‪就是你
♪ You, you ♪
‪在我茶里的蜜糖其实就是你
♪ The honey in my tea, you knowIs you, you ♪
‪滚烫的泡沫
‪就是你
♪ You, you ♪
♪ The bubbles in the boil ♪
‪缺一不可的香精油
♪ The one essential oilIt's true ♪
‪秘方的秘密其实就是你
♪ The secret to the formulaIs you, you ♪
‪就是你
‪海绵宝宝！
-SpongeBob!-♪ You, you ♪
‪秘方的秘密其实就是你
♪ The secret to the formula ♪
-♪ Is you, you ♪-[laughs]
‪真是精彩万分！
So entertaining!
‪秘方的秘密其实就是你
♪ The secret to the formulaIs you, you ♪
‪就是你
♪ You, you ♪
Yeehaw!
[applause, cheering]
‪真有趣！
Ha! Hilarious!
[laughing]
Hmm?
‪我的蜗牛！
My snail!
Wha--? Huh?
‪停止！这是个把戏！快捉住他们！
Halt! It's a trick! Seize them!
‪盖瑞 你又回到我身边了‪我再也不会让任何人把你带走
Gary, you're with me now.
I'll never let anyone take you again.
[meows]
‪快！
[Plankton] Faster!
[Patrick] Oh!
‪哇
Wow.
‪-派大星 你在做什么？‪-免费的食物！
Yah! Patrick, what are you doing?
Free food!
[screams]
[yells]
‪捉住他！
Get him!
[all shouting]
‪快来这里！
Come on, come on. In here!
‪站住！
[soldier] Stop right there!
‪快进去！
-[loud thud]-Inside! Quick!
[gasps]
[grunting]
‪快啊！
Come on!
‪糟糕
Uh-oh.
‪快用力推 痞老板！
Push! Push, Plankton!
‪开什么玩笑？
You got to be kidding me!
Hah!
[grunts]
Hmm?
[all exclaiming]
‪逮到你了！
Peekaboo!
‪进攻！
[cackles] Attack!
Ha-hah!
‪快进攻！
-Attack!-[yelling]
‪大家当心左侧！
Whoa!Watch your left flank, people!
‪击剑！还击！
Thrust! Now parry!
‪转圈 再转过来 竖趾旋转
Now pirouette.Turn around. Pivot!
‪用力拉 快！往右边！
Pull harder. Faster!To the right!
Hi-ya!
[Plankton] Whoa, whoa! [yells]
[bowling strike sound]
[both yelp]
[shrieking]
[screaming]
‪我们是否该选择留在章鱼哥那里？
Do you think we should'vestayed in there with Squidward?
‪没事 他行的
Nah, he's got it.
‪大家去哪了？
[Squidward] Where is everybody?!
‪进攻！
Charge!
-[Squidward] Whoa!-[sizzling]
[shrieking]
‪-章鱼哥！‪-章鱼哥！
-[yelling]-Squidward!
[all yelling]
[screams]
‪章鱼哥！这里！
Squidward! Fall this way!
‪不 这里！
No, this way!
[Patrick] Oh.
‪有人员倒下了
Man down.
‪接得好
Good catch.
‪-嘿 他们在那里！‪-快捉住他们！
-Hey, there they are!-Get them!
‪嘿 你们好啊？
Yo, what's up?
‪奥托！
Otto!
‪我沉迷于赌博
I have a gambling problem.
‪奥托！
Otto!
‪有谁能借钱给我？
Could anyone lend me some money?
‪开往比奇堡！加速！
To Bikini Bottom!And step on it!
‪正在加速中
Stepping on it.
‪你们全都被解雇了
You're all fired.
‪前往代客泊车服务处！
To the valet!
-Ah!-[gasping]
‪这么快就走了吗 孩子们？
Leaving so soon, kids?
[anxious meow]
‪撑着 盖瑞 我会抓紧你的
Hang on, Gary.I won't let you go.
‪你们可真没礼貌 对吧？
Tsk, tsk. Rather impolite,don't you think?
‪这全都是他们的主意 殿下
It was all their idea, sire.
‪我…
And I…
‪爱死了！
…loved it!
‪等等 你没生我们的气？
Wait, so you're not mad at us?
‪没有 我已经好久没享受过‪如此精彩的表演
[laughing] No!
It's been a while since I've enjoyed
such toe-tapping entertainment.
‪-一切都被赦免了！取消所有控诉‪-太好了！
All is forgiven!
-And all charges are dropped.-Hooray!
‪但有一个条件
On one condition.
‪海绵宝宝将归还我的蜗牛‪别再耍花样了
SpongeBob will return my snail to me
without any more shilly-shally.
‪等等 什么？
Wait, what?
‪只要把蜗牛交出 你们全都能离开
Just hand over the snailand you can all go free.
‪但是我…
But… I… I…
‪海绵宝宝
[Sage] SpongeBob.
‪风滚草基哥？是你吗？
[Spongebob] Sage? Is that you?
‪你好啊
Hello.
‪风滚草基哥！嗨！
Sage! Hi!
‪切记
Remember…
‪你所寻的英勇来自你内心
The courage you seekis inside you.
‪在你英勇不足时 给予你勇气
And it will come to youin your hour of need.
‪勇气源自我内心
[Spongebob] The courage is inside me.
‪勇气源自我内心！
The courage is inside me!
‪波塞冬先生 不行
Mr. Poseidon, no.
‪很抱歉 但我不会这么做
I'm sorry, but I won't do it.
‪什么？
[laughs]
‪我太爱盖瑞 他也爱我
What?I love Gary too much,and he loves me.
‪我们若没有彼此都会很难过
If we didn't have each other,we'd be so sad. Well…
‪无论你对我们做些什么都无所谓
It wouldn't really matterwhat you'd do to us.
[meows]
‪今天多谢我这些很棒的朋友们
And look. Today, thanks to theseamazing friends,
‪我内心感到前所未有过的澎湃
my heart feels twice as biga s it ever did.
‪尤其是他们为我铤而走险
Especially after what they risked for me:
‪藐视法律并对抗强大的海洋之王
Flouting the law and defyingthe mighty king of the sea.
‪对抗？不是吧？
Defying? Really?
‪那当然不算是对抗国王
I wouldn't say defying the king.
‪在你臣子面前羞辱你
Humiliating you in front of your subjects.
‪-继续说下去‪-那更像是钦佩您的美德
-Do go on.-More like admiring.
‪我完全赞同！
And totally agreeing with!
‪我只是来看凯尔皮G的演出
I just came to see Kelpy G.
‪他们全都为了我
And they did it all for me.
‪你若有像他们这样的朋友‪肯定能理解
I'm sure you'd understandif you had friends like these.
‪像他们这样的朋友？你在说些什么？
Friends like these?Wait, what?
‪像他们这样的朋友？
Friends like these?
‪我当然有像他们这样的朋友‪我交友满天下！
[chuckles] Of course I havefriends like these.
I have all kinds of friends!
‪我有好哥们也有死党
I have buddies, I have besties.
‪有好朋友也有普通朋友
I have home-slices, palsy-walsies.
‪我的友谊无限！
It's infinite!
‪大臣！快计算出我朋友的数据
Chancellor! Give us an exact number.
The friend count, if you will.
‪好的 根据您最新的民调数据
Uh, okay,according to your latest polling data,
‪我们应该先获得更多的民调数据
we should get more polling data.
‪把那个给我
What? Give me that.
‪（喜欢指数：0‪讨厌指数：100）
Huh?
‪我的粉丝们呢？
What about my adoring fans?
‪-没有‪-我的精英宫殿卫队呢？
-Nope.-My elite palace guards?
‪我的私人教练呢？
-Mm-mm.-[innocent whistling]
-What about my personal trainer?-Mmm… Mm-mm.
‪-我的治疗师？‪-全都没有
-My therapist?-Nada.
‪-我的纹身去除师傅？‪-什么也没有
‪-我的纹身师傅？‪-还是没有
-My tattoo artist?-Uh…nope.
-My tattoo removal artist?-No dice.
‪你身为我忠心耿耿的大臣‪肯定有吧？
B-But surely you, my chancellor,
my loyal faithful…?
‪抱歉
Sorry.
[sobs]
‪阿波罗 带我走吧
Apollo, take me now.
‪我没有任何朋友！
I don't have any friends!
‪你现在有一个朋友了！
Well, you got one now!
‪真的？是谁？
Really? Who is it?
‪是我！我来做你的朋友吧！
It's me! I'll be your friend.
‪你是说真的？
Do you mean it?
‪是的 但朋友不会绑架‪朋友的宠物蜗牛
Yes. But friends don't kidnapfriends' pet snails.
‪但我很需要那只蜗牛
-[meows]-But I need that snail.
‪看这里 我有一道很恶心的皱纹
Look, I have a horrible,disgusting wrinkle.
‪该死的 这跟马里亚纳海沟一样深！
Jumping jellyfish,it's the size of the Mariana Trench!
‪我开玩笑的 样貌根本不重要
-[moaning sob]-[laughs] Kidding!
Looks don't matter.
‪我们才不在乎细小的不完美‪甚至是大缺陷！
We don't care about little imperfections.
Or even big ones!
‪-你看看章鱼哥就明白了‪-你这是什么意思？
-Just look at Squidward.-What's that supposed to mean?
‪重要的是你内在的美好
What's important is what's inside.
‪你肯定能成为所有海洋生物‪公正善良的国王
And I'm sure you can bea fair and kind king
to all the creatures of the sea.
‪你行的 殿下‪你只需抛开三千烦恼丝
I know you've got it in you, sir.
If you'd just let your hair down a little.
‪什么？我的头发吗？等等
Huh? My hair? Wait a minute.
‪你是说我不需要‪这头乌黑亮丽的秀发？
Are you suggesting that I don't need this
gorgeous mane of wavy locks?
[cheering]
‪我也不需要这个颈夹？
That I don't require this neck clip?
[gasping]
[cheering]
‪也不需要完美洁白的牙齿！
Be gone, perfect shiny teeth!
‪这感觉太解放了！
This is so freeing!
‪也不要这胸板和腰带
To heck with this chest plate and girdle.
No! Not at all!
‪你看上去棒极了！
[all overlapping]No, you look great!
‪谢谢你！这真是振奋人心
Oh, thank you!I find this so exhilarating.
‪也很符合我的年龄
So… age appropriate.
‪海绵宝宝 没几个人有勇气‪对抗一个强大的国王
SpongeBob, few possess the courage
to stand up to a powerful king.
‪而你是少数中的佼佼者 我向你致敬
You, sir, are among those few.I salute you.
‪你做得好极了 海绵宝宝
Nailed it, SpongeBob.
‪风滚草基哥告退了
Sage out.
‪你留下盖瑞吧‪我祝福你们能共度许多开心的时光
You may keep Gary.
And I wish you many happy years together.
‪谢谢！你听到了吗 盖瑞宝贝？
Thank you!Did you hear that, Gare-Bear?
[meows]
‪请穿上皇袍 殿下 这里很冷
Uh, your royal robe, Your Highness.
‪胡说八道 大臣‪我此刻已彻底解放天性！
-It's getting cold out here.-Nonsense, Chancellor.
I'm free!
‪您绝对是的
Ooh, you certainly are.
‪释放所有蜗牛！
And free the snails!
[all meowing]
‪你说什么？
[Gary meows]
What's that?
‪把它们全都带回家？
All of them?
["Take On Me" playing]
‪我到家了！
I'm home!
[meows]
‪你好啊 盖瑞
Hello, Gary.
‪你好啊 布莱恩
Hello, Brian.
‪你好啊 珍娜 还有琼和露比
Hello, Janet. Hello, June.Hola, Lupe.
‪-早安 萨利！‪-嗨 布雷特！
-Morning, Sally!-Hi, Brett!
[snails meowing]
-[snails meowing]-[indistinct chatter]
‪（领养蜗牛）
‪妈妈 快点！
‪来吧 盖瑞！你行的！
Come on, Gary! You can do it!
[errified meow]
‪好极了！
Yeah!
‪（若有蜗牛走失 请联系派大星）
‪法比欧！你在哪 朋友？
Fabio! Where are you, buddy?
‪快来这里 法比欧！
Here, Fabio, Fabio, Fabio!
‪来吧 菲菲 不
Come on, Fifi. No.
-[snails purring]-[Plankton groans]
[laughing]
‪（蟹堡王）
‪上菜！
Order up!
‪（比奇堡）
[crowing]
‪（蜗牛避难所）
‪（缅怀斯蒂芬海伦伯格）
["Agua" playing]
[no audible dialogue]
[song continues]
["Krabby Step" playing]
["Snail: I'm Avail" playing]
["Gary's song" playing]
‪字幕翻译：宋氏